<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>heat@iclei.org</title>
	<atom:link href="https://heat.iclei.org/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://heat.iclei.org/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 19:03:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://heat.iclei.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/live-favicon.jpg</url>
	<title>heat@iclei.org</title>
	<link>https://heat.iclei.org/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Indian scientists develop new tech for Open Radio Access Network stations</title>
		<link>https://heat.iclei.org/indian-scientists-develop-new-tech-for-open-radio-access-network-stations/</link>
					<comments>https://heat.iclei.org/indian-scientists-develop-new-tech-for-open-radio-access-network-stations/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 15:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science & Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indian scientists develop new tech for Open Radio Access Network stations]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://heat.iclei.org/?p=620</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A new niche technological solution for Open Radio Access Network (ORAN) base stations has been developed by Indian scientists that is expected to facilitate high-speed and reliable connectivity at a cost viable for unconnected and far-flung areas. The best-in-class ORAN...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">A new niche technological solution for Open Radio Access Network (ORAN) base stations has been developed by Indian scientists that is expected to facilitate high-speed and reliable connectivity at a cost viable for unconnected and far-flung areas. The best-in-class ORAN base station solution has been designed and is under development for commercialisation for creating spectral and energy-efficient wireless communications technology for 5G and 5G-Advanced radio networks, the Science and Technology Ministry said in a recent statement.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">ORAN base station solutions, a critical component of next-generation telecommunications infrastructure, disaggregates the software and hardware components of the network infrastructure. ORAN-based interfaces are like doors that provide access to different components of the network infrastructure making it easier, efficient, and more economically viable to provide internet in remote areas. The breaking down of the Radio Access Network (RAN) functions helps bring down network cost and complexity. Open RAN removes vendor lock-in and can facilitate smooth interoperation between cellular network equipment provided by different vendors.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The ORAN base station radio unit development led by Dr. Kiran Kuchi, Professor at Indian Institute of Technology in Hyderabad introduced the ORAN technology harnessing a multitude of antennas on cell towers. The &#8220;breakthrough&#8221; promises to not only enhance cell coverage but also boost capacity by an impressive three-fold compared to existing 4G networks, thereby optimising spectrum utilisation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://heat.iclei.org/indian-scientists-develop-new-tech-for-open-radio-access-network-stations/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bluesky Is No Longer Invite-only</title>
		<link>https://heat.iclei.org/bluesky-is-no-longer-invite-only/</link>
					<comments>https://heat.iclei.org/bluesky-is-no-longer-invite-only/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 15:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science & Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bluesky Is No Longer Invite-only]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://heat.iclei.org/?p=623</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Bluesky, a micro-blogging platform founded by Twitter co-founder Jack Dorsey, has officially opened its doors to the public after nearly a year as an invite-only app. With an initial user base of 3 million sign-ups during its closed beta phase,...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Bluesky, a micro-blogging platform founded by Twitter co-founder Jack Dorsey, has officially opened its doors to the public after nearly a year as an invite-only app. With an initial user base of 3 million sign-ups during its closed beta phase, the social media app features an open-source decentralised infrastructure. Bluesky&#8217;s user interface closely resembles that of Twitter, providing a familiar experience for users. However, the platform&#8217;s true innovation lies in its decentralised infrastructure. The AT Protocol, originally developed within Twitter, has been designed to create a decentralised environment for social networking. This decentralised approach allows for greater transparency and flexibility, as the entire codebase of Bluesky is open source.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Being open source means that anyone, including developers outside the company, can access and scrutinise the code. According to the platform, this transparency fosters trust among users and provides insights into the platform&#8217;s inner workings. Additionally, developers have the freedom to contribute to the project and even build their applications or features on top of the AT Protocol.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">While the open-source, decentralised platform has its notable perk over other notably newer micro-blogging platforms Mastodon and Threads, it has a long way to go in building a user base that can sufficiently rival such platforms. However, with the recent shift to now being open to everyone, the open-source AT Protocol codebase is expected to attract third-party developers that might redefine the micro-blogging landscape as we know it. You can sign up for Bluesky by going here, registering via your email, and verifying with your phone number. However, please note that at the time of writing, Bluesky is unable to send verification messages to phone numbers in Bangladesh.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://heat.iclei.org/bluesky-is-no-longer-invite-only/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Did you know an Indian startup 3D-printed a house in 21 days</title>
		<link>https://heat.iclei.org/did-you-know-an-indian-startup-3d-printed-a-house-in-21-days/</link>
					<comments>https://heat.iclei.org/did-you-know-an-indian-startup-3d-printed-a-house-in-21-days/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 15:41:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science & Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Did you know an Indian startup 3D-printed a house in 21 days]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://heat.iclei.org/?p=617</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On April 27, 2021, Tvasta, a startup founded by alumni from the Indian Institute of Technology Madras, completed the construction of India&#8217;s first 3D-printed house, in only 21 days. Modules for this 500 sq. ft. house were printed in the...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">On April 27, 2021, Tvasta, a startup founded by alumni from the Indian Institute of Technology Madras, completed the construction of India&#8217;s first 3D-printed house, in only 21 days. Modules for this 500 sq. ft. house were printed in the startup&#8217;s facility in Chennai and assembled at the site, as per the company&#8217;s official website.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>How was this done?</strong><br />
The house was built using 3D-printed modules, using a process that involves layer-by-layer deposition of materials to create three-dimensional structures. Such processes typically utilise large-scale 3D printers capable of handling construction materials such as concrete, polymers, or other suitable building materials. According to Tvasta, 3D printing for construction leads to an 80% reduction in waste, and can significantly reduce labour requirements and time of construction.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Google News LinkFor all latest news, follow The Daily Star&#8217;s Google News channel.</strong><br />
The construction of this unique structure cost Rs 5 to 5.5 lakh, which, is about 20% of the cost of a standard 2BHK apartment in India, as per a 2022 report by the Indian news portal The Better India. The report adds that the technology used by Tvasta creates only 1/3rd of the waste generated using conventional building methods.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Tvasta: vision and goals</strong><br />
According to Tvasta&#8217;s website, the startup was founded with the vision of &#8220;leveraging 3D printing technology to revolutionise home construction&#8221;. In an interview with The Better India, Adithya VS, co-founder and CEO of the startup, noted that by using a 3D printer capable of receiving instructions on building large-scale structures in the form of a 3D virtual file, &#8220;a large-scale structure can be built without formwork or moulds in a very short period through layer-by-layer manufacturing&#8221;.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In a similar interview, Vidyashankar C, COO of Tvasta, said that the startup enables &#8220;mass customisation of end components&#8221; and that by using their 3D printing technology, any construction project can be done in minimum time with minimum impact on the environment. As per their website, the startup plans to &#8220;develop category-creating platform technologies that aim to disrupt the construction industry by automating 80% of construction&#8221;.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>3D-printed statue</strong><br />
&#8216;Anant Siras&#8217;, a 21-foot statue, was printed, assembled, and finished by Tvasta in a month. They have also built &#8216;Anant Siras&#8217; a 21-foot statue commemorating 75 years of India Cement, which was printed, assembled, and finished in a month.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://heat.iclei.org/did-you-know-an-indian-startup-3d-printed-a-house-in-21-days/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
